<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A charter of regulations granted to the East-India Company by Their sacred Majesties King William and Queen Mary, under the Great Seal of England, Dated the 11th. of November, 1693. in the 5th. year of Their Majesties reign</title>
            <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1689-1694 : William and Mary)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1693</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 46 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 6 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A66230</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing W2498A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R219989</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99831429</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99831429</idno>
            <idno type="VID">35892</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A66230)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 35892)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 2121:05)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A charter of regulations granted to the East-India Company by Their sacred Majesties King William and Queen Mary, under the Great Seal of England, Dated the 11th. of November, 1693. in the 5th. year of Their Majesties reign</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1689-1694 : William and Mary)</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>11, [1] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1693]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Place of publication from Wing.</note>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>With marginal notes.</note>
                  <note>Copy has print show-through.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>East India Company --  Charters --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-10</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11</date>
            <label>Pip Willcox</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11</date>
            <label>Pip Willcox</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="charter">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:35892:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>A <hi>CHARTER</hi> of Regulations Granted to the <hi>East-India</hi> Company by Their Sacred Majeſties King <hi>WILLIAM</hi> and Queen <hi>MARY,</hi> under the Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> Dated the 11th. of <hi>November,</hi> 1693. in the 5th. Year of Their Majeſties Reign.</head>
            <opener>
               <signed>
                  <note place="margin">
                     <hi>WILLIAM</hi> and <hi>MARY</hi> by the Grace of God King and Queen of <hi>England,</hi> &amp;c.</note>WILLIAM and MARY,</signed>
            </opener>
            <p>By the Grace of God King and Queen of <hi>England, Scotland, France</hi> and <hi>Ireland,</hi> Defenders of the Faith, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> To all to whom theſe Preſents ſhall come Greeting.<note place="margin">Whereas the Governour and Company of Merchants of <hi>London</hi> Trading into the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> have been long a Cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poration, to the Honour and Profit ot this Nation, And enjoyed divers Immu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nities by vertue of ſeveral Charters;</note>
               <hi>Whereas</hi> the Governour and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany of Merchants of <hi>London</hi> Trading into the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> have been of long time to the Honour and Profit of this Nation, a Corporation, and have enjoy'd divers Liberties, Priviledges and Immunities, by force of ſeveral Charters and Letters Patents here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tofore granted to them by ſeveral of our late Royal Predeceſſors, More particularly by Letters Patents of our late Royal Uncle, King <hi>Charles</hi> the Second, under the Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi>
               <note place="margin">VIZ,</note> bearing date the third day of <hi>April,</hi> in the 13th. Year of his Reign; And by one other Charter, or Letters Patents, of the ſaid King <hi>Charles</hi> the Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cond, under the Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> bearing date at <hi>Weſtminſter</hi> the 27th. day of <hi>March,</hi> in the 20th. Year of his Reign; And by one other Charter, or Letters Patents of the ſaid King <hi>Charles</hi> the Second bearing date at <hi>Weſtminſter</hi> the 16th. day of <hi>December</hi> in the 25th. Year of his Reign; And by one other Charter, or Letters Patents of the ſaid late King <hi>Charles</hi> the Second, bearing date the 9th. day of <hi>Auguſt,</hi> in the 35th. Year of his Reign; And alſo by a Charter or Letters Patents of the late King <hi>James</hi> the Second bear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing date at <hi>Weſtminſter</hi> the 12th. day of <hi>April,</hi> in the Second Year of his Reign:<note place="margin">And whereas ſome doubt hath ariſen touching the Validity of the Charters heretofore granted to the ſaid Company,</note> And whereas ſome doubt or Queſtion having been lately made, touching the Validity of the Charters granted hereto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore by our late Royal Predeceſſors Kings and Queens of <hi>England,</hi> to the Governour and Company of Merchants of <hi>London</hi> Trading into the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> and whether the ſame were not in ſtrictneſs of Law void by the not actual Payment into the Receipt of our <hi>Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chequer,</hi>
               <note place="margin">By the not actual Payment of the firſt Quarterly Pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of the 5 <hi>
                     <abbr>l.</abbr> per Cent.</hi> Tax.</note> of the firſt Quarterly Payment of the Tax of five pounds <hi>per Cent.</hi> charged on the General Joynt-Stock of the ſaid Company; according to a late Act of Parliament Entituled, <hi>(An Act for con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinuing certain Acts therein mentioned, and for charging ſeveral Joynt-Stocks)</hi> And We having taken the ſame into our Royal Conſidera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion,<note place="margin">We, well weighing the Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>orders that would happen if advantage were taken of the ſaid Forfeiture,</note> and well weighing what Diſorders and Inconveniences would befall the ſaid Company, and other Perſons concerned and employed in their Trade and Adventures, eſpecially in the remote parts of the World, if we ſhould have taken advantage of the Forfeiture afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, Did by our Letters Patents under our Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi>
               <note place="margin">Did by our Letters Patents, dated the 7th. of <hi>October</hi> laſt, Conſtitute Sir <hi>Thomas Cooke, Francis Tyſſen,</hi>
                  <abbr>Eſq</abbr>
                  <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </note> bearing date the 7th. day of <hi>October</hi> now laſt paſt, make, conſtitute, ordain, declare and appoint that Sir <hi>Thomas Cooke</hi> Knt. and one of the Aldermen of our City of <hi>London, Francis Tyſſen</hi>
               <abbr>Eſq</abbr>
               <hi>George</hi> Earl
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:35892:2"/>of <hi>Berkeley,</hi> Sir <hi>John Fleet,</hi> Knt. then Lord Mayor of our City of <hi>London,</hi> Sir <hi>Joſia Child</hi> Baronet, Sir <hi>William Langhorne,</hi> Baronet, Sir <hi>Benjamin Bathurſt</hi> Knt. Sir <hi>John Moore</hi> Knt. and one of the Aldermen of our City of <hi>London,</hi> Sir <hi>Sam. Daſhwood</hi> Knt. and one of the Aldermen of our City of <hi>London,</hi> Sir <hi>Edward des Bouvery</hi> Knt. Sir <hi>Thomas Rawlinſon,</hi> Knt. Sir <hi>William Gore,</hi> Knt. and one of the Aldermen of our City of <hi>London,</hi> Sir <hi>Joſeph Herne</hi> Knt. Sir <hi>Rowland Aynſworth,</hi> Knt. <hi>John Pery</hi>
               <abbr>Eſq</abbr>
               <hi>George Boun</hi>
               <abbr>Eſq</abbr>
               <hi>Richard Hutchin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon,</hi> Jun. <abbr>Eſq</abbr>
               <hi>Frederick Herne,</hi>
               <abbr>Eſq</abbr>
               <hi>Ralph Marſhall</hi>
               <abbr>Eſq</abbr>
               <hi>Richard Acton, John Cooke</hi> of <hi>Hackney, Francis Gosfright, John Da Bois, Iſaac Houblon, Samuel Ongley</hi> and <hi>Nath. Mounteney</hi> Gentlemen, and all and every other Perſon and Perſon who were Members of the ſaid Company,<note place="margin">And all other the Members of the ſaid or late Company, on the 24th. <hi>March</hi> laſt,</note> or late Company of Merchants of <hi>London</hi> Trading into the <hi>Eaſt-Indies</hi> on the 24th. day of <hi>March</hi> now laſt paſt, who had not before the Date of the ſaid laſt recited Letters Patents parted with their Stocks in the ſaid Company,<note place="margin">Who had not parted with their Stocks;</note> and all and every other Perſon and Perſons who after the ſaid 24th. day of <hi>March</hi> laſt paſt, and before the date of the ſaid laſt recited Letters Patents,<note place="margin">And all others who by buy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Stocks, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Were capable to be Mem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bers of the ſaid Company, To be one Body Politick, By the Name of the Gover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour and Company of Mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chants of <hi>London,</hi> Trading into the <hi>Eaſt-Indies.</hi>
               </note> by buying Stocks or otherwiſe, had come into, and then remained in a Capacity of being Members of the ſaid Company, ſhould be a Body Corpo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rate and Politique in Deed and in Name, by the Name of the <hi>Governour and Company of Merchants of London Trading into the Eaſt-Indies,</hi> And them, by that Name, one Body Corporate and Politique, in Deed and in Name, really and fully for ever, for Us our Heirs and Succeſſors, We did make, declare, eſtabliſh and con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>firm; And we have alſo in and by the ſaid laſt recited Letters Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tents for Us,<note place="margin">And granted and reſtored unto them all the Ports, Iſlands, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </note> Our Heirs and Succeſſors, given, granted, reſtored and confirmed unto the ſaid Governour and Company thereby con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtituted and confirmed, and their Succeſſors, All and every the Ports, Iſlands, Plantations, Territories, Caſtles, Forts, Fortifications, Ordnance, Armour, Artillery, Munition, Arms, Guns, Powder, Shot, Victuals, Magazines, Stores, Ammunition and Proviſions of War, Ships, Junks, Veſſels, Boats, Joynt Stock, Mannors, Lordſhips, Meſſuages, Houſes, Lands, Tenements, Hereditaments, Goods, Wares, Merchandizes, Cattle, Chattels real and perſonal, Debts, Dues, Duties, right of Actions and Demand in Law or Equity, Powers, Priviledges, Liberties, Franchiſes, Juriſdictions, Cuſtomes, Rights, Royalties, Immunities and Advantages what<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſoever,<note place="margin">Which were or might be lawfully enjoyed by them, on or before the 24th. <hi>March</hi> laſt, or ſince,</note> and all other things which were lawfully held, received, uſed, exerciſed, or enjoyed, or might or ought to have been law<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fully held, received, uſed, exerciſed, or enjoyed by the ſaid Gover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour and Company, or late Governour and Company of Merchants of <hi>London,</hi> Trading into the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> on or before the ſaid 24th. day of <hi>March</hi> now laſt, or at any time before the Date of the ſaid laſt recited Letters,<note place="margin">By Vertue of any Charters formerly granted or confir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>med to them:</note> Patents, by Force or Vertue of any Grants, Charters, or Letters Patents whatſoever, thentofore granted unto them, or mentioned to be granted or confirmed to them, by any of our late Royal Predeceſſors, Kings or Queens of <hi>England,</hi> by any Stile or Title of Incorporation whatſoever, or otherwiſe howſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ever; To have,<note place="margin">To enjoy the Premiſes to the ſaid Governour and Company</note> hold, exerciſe and enjoy the Premiſes to the ſaid Governour and Company, or late Governour and Company of Merchants of <hi>London</hi> Trading into the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> and their Suc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſors, in ſuch and the ſame manner, and to and for ſuch and the ſame Intents and Purpoſes in all things,<note place="margin">In the ſame manner as they might have done on the 24th. <hi>March</hi> laſt.</note> as the ſaid Governour and Company, or late Governour and Company might or ought law<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fully to have had, held, uſed, exerciſed or enjoyed the ſame, on or at any time before the ſaid 24th. day of <hi>March</hi> now laſt paſt, as if the ſame Powers, Priviledges, and Immunities, and other the
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:35892:2"/>Premiſes,<note place="margin">And the Powers by the ſaid Charter, had been particu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>larly recited: Bu<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> under the limitations therein contained.</note> had been by the ſaid laſt recited Letters Patents particu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>larly granted, and the Letters Patents concerning the ſame at large recited, Under and ſubject nevertheleſs to the Proviſoes, Reſtrictions and Limitations contained in the ſaid laſt recited Letters Patents, and in other the Charters formerly granted to the ſaid Company. And <hi>Whereas,</hi>
               <note place="margin">And whereas, in the ſaid Charter of the 7th. <hi>October</hi> is contained the Proviſo fol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowing, <hi>Viz.</hi>
               </note> in the ſaid laſt recited Letters Patents bearing date the 7th. day of <hi>October</hi> now laſt paſt, there is contained a Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viſoe or Condition in the Words following, (Viz.) <hi>Provided always,</hi> and upon Condition Nevertheleſs, and Our Expreſs Will and mean<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing is, That if the ſaid <hi>Governour and Company of Merchants of</hi> London <hi>Trading into the</hi> Eaſt-Indies, and their Succeſſors, do not accept of, and from time to time,<note place="margin">If the Company do not ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cept of, and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>fectually exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>c<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>e ſuch directions, are rations, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </note> and at all times hereafter Act ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to, and put in due and effectual Execution, and ſubmit and conform in all things unto ſuch Orders, Directions, Additions, Al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terations, Reſtrictions and Qualifications relating to the Conſtitu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, Continuance, Determination, Rights, Powers or Priviledges of the ſaid Company, or the Government thereof, Or of the ſaid Governour and Company or the Incouragement, Management, Regulation or Advancement of Trade, Or of the preſent or future Joynt-Stock of the ſaid Company, Or concerning any future Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcriptions to be made by way of Increaſe or Addition to the Joynt-Stock, Or for aſcertaining the true Values of the ſaid Joynt Stock, at and during the time of any ſuch future Subſcriptions, which, and as We, Our Heirs or Succeſſors,<note place="margin">At we ſhall make before the 29th. <hi>September,</hi> 1694.</note> by the Advice of our or their Privy Council, ſhall from time to time at any time before the 29th. day of <hi>September,</hi> which ſhall be in the Year 1694. think fit to make, inſert, limit, direct, appoint or expreſs in or by any further or other Charter, Letters Patents, or other Writing or Inſtrument under our or their Great Seal of <hi>England;</hi>
               <note place="margin">Then theſe preſents to be re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vokable,</note> Then and in each and every of the Caſes aforeſaid, It ſhall and may be lawful to and for Us, Our Heirs and Succeſſors, by Letters Patents under our or their Great Seal of <hi>England</hi> to determine, revoke and make void theſe preſents, and the Grant hereby made, And from and immediately after the paſſing of ſuch Letters Patents of Revocation or Determination under the Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> Theſe preſents, and all the Powers,<note place="margin">And all the Powers therein contained to ceaſe.</note> Priviledges, Grants and other things herein contained ſhall ceaſe, determine and be abſolutely void to all Intents and Purpoſes, any thing to the contrary notwithſtanding, As in and by the ſaid laſt re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cited Letters Patents (amongſt ſeveral other Proviſoes, Powers and Clauſes therein contained) relation being thereunto had, may more fully and at large appear. <hi>NOW KNOW YE,</hi>
               <note place="margin">
                  <hi>NOW KNOW YE,</hi> That we conſidering how highly it Imports this Kingdom, that the <hi>Eaſt-India</hi> Trade ſhould be continued,</note> That We conſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dering how highly it Imports the Honour and Welfare of this our Kingdom, and our Subjects thereof, That a Trade and Traffique to the <hi>Eaſt-Indies</hi> ſhould be continued, And being well ſatisfied that the ſame may be of great and publick Advantage,<note place="margin">And being deſirous to make the ſame more National,</note> And being alſo deſirous to render the ſame (as much as in us lies) more National, General and Extenſive than hitherto it hath been (which will be beſt carried on and effected by a General Joynt-Stock) Have,<note place="margin">(which is beſt to be done in a Joynt-Stock,) have for the Purpoſes afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid,</note> to and for the ends and purpoſes aforeſaid, and in purſuance and part of the Execution of the Power to us reſerved in and by the ſaid Proviſoe in our ſaid Letters Patents, and herein before-mentioned, by and with the Advice of our Privy Council, and of our eſpecial Grace,<note place="margin">by the Advice of our Privy Council, and of our Eſpecial Grace, certain Knowledge and mere Motion, ordained and conſtituted:</note> certain Knowledge and mere Motion, ordained, conſtituted and appointed, And by theſe Preſents for Us, our Heirs and Succeſſors, do Order, direct, ordain, conſtitute and appoint, and the ſaid <hi>Governour and Company of Merchants of</hi> London <hi>Trading into the</hi> Eaſt-Indies,<note place="margin">And the ſaid Company de agree to.</note> do hereby accept and agree to, That all and every Perſon and Perſons,
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:35892:3"/>as well our Natural born Subjects of this our Kingdom,<note place="margin">That all our Subjects, and Perſons Naturaliz'd and In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deniz'd, who ſhall hereafter Subſcribe and pay down the Summes of Money by them Subſcribed in ſuch manner as is herein after-directed, ſhall be Members of the ſaid Company, as is after ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>preſſed.</note> as Perſons Naturaliz'd and endenized, who ſhall hereafter ſubſcribe and pay down the ſeveral Proportions of the reſpective Sums of Money by them reſpectively Subſcribed, in ſuch manner as the ſame is herein after directed and appointed to be Subſcribed and paid, be, and by the <hi>Governour and Company of Merchants of</hi> London <hi>Trading into the</hi> Eaſt-Indies, for the time being, ſhall be admitted and become Members of the ſaid Company within the time, and in the man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner herein after for that purpoſe expreſſed. And our Will and Pleaſure is,<note place="margin">And Our Will and Pleaſure is, That,</note> And we do hereby for Us, our Heirs and Succeſſors, grant unto the ſaid <hi>Governour and Company of Merchants of</hi> London <hi>Trading into the</hi> Eaſt-Indies, and their Succeſſors, And do hereby order,<note place="margin">744000 <abbr>
                     <hi>l.</hi>
                  </abbr> be Subſcribed</note> direct and appoint, That the Sum of 744000 <abbr>l.</abbr> of Lawful Money of <hi>England,</hi> ſhall and may be added to the preſent General Joynt-Stock of the ſaid Company, by the New Subſcriptions of ſuch Perſons who ſhall be minded to adventure any ſhare in the General Joynt-Stock of the ſaid Company, and to be paid in to the uſe of the ſaid Company, in ſuch manner and proportions, and within ſuch time as is herein after-mentioned, for the carrying on and managing a Trade to the <hi>Eaſt-Indies</hi> by a General Joynt-Stock. And for the purpoſes aforeſaid, We do hereby, for us, our Heirs, and Succeſſors, Order, Direct, and Appoint, that a Book, or Books, made of Vellum for the ſaid New Subſcriptions to be Inſerted,<note place="margin">in a Book of Vellum. (within Six days to be provided,)</note> ſhall be provided within Six Days, after the Date hereof, by the ſaid Gover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour and Company of Merchants of <hi>London</hi> Trading into the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> which ſhall lie open every Day in the Week (<hi>Sundays</hi> ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cepted) at the <hi>Eaſt-India</hi> Houſe in <hi>Leaden-Hall-street,</hi>
               <note place="margin">to he open daily from Eight to Twelve, in the Morning and from Two to Six in the Afternoon, till the 10th. <hi>January</hi> next.</note>
               <hi>London,</hi> from the Hour of Eight to the Hour of Twelve in the Morning, and from the Hour of Two to the Hour of Six in the Afternoon, untill the Tenth day of <hi>January</hi> next incluſive; In which ſaid Book or Books, it ſhall and may be lawful to and for any perſon or perſons whatſoever, being Natural born Subjects of this Our Realm and Perſons Naturalized or Endenized, to pay and Subſcribe on or be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the ſaid 10th. day of <hi>January</hi> now next enſuing, ſuch Sum and Sums of Money, to be added to the preſent Joynt-Stock of the ſaid Company, as they ſhall think fit to Adventure in the ſaid Trade, So as no one perſon ſhall ſubſcribe more than the Sum of Ten Thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſand Pounds;<note place="margin">None to Subſcribe above 10000.</note> And We do hereby for Us, Our Heirs and Succeſſors, direct and appoint, That if it ſhall happen, That the New Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcriptions to be made by virtue of theſe Preſents, ſhall exceed the Sum of 744000 <abbr>l.</abbr> in the whole,<note place="margin">If the Subſcriptions exceed 744000 <abbr>
                     <hi>l.</hi>
                  </abbr> to be reduced to that Summe by the Court of Committees.</note> That then and in ſuch caſe the Governour or Deputy Governour, and the Court of Committees of the ſaid Company (to be qualified in ſuch manner as is herein after expreſſed) ſhall leſſen and reduce the ſaid New Subſcriptions, to the ſaid Sum of 744000 <abbr>l.</abbr>
               <hi>rata pro rata,</hi> and in proportion to the ſeveral Sums ſo newly Subſcribed to the Joynt-Stock of the ſaid Company. And Our further Will and Pleaſure is, And we do hereby for Us, Our Heirs and Succeſſors, Order and appoint, That all and every Perſon and Perſons ſo ſubſcribing, ſhall at the time of his or her Subſcription,<note place="margin">The Subſcribers to ſwear the Moneys ſubſcribed is their own, and for their own uſe, and not in truſt.</note> reſpectively take an Oath before the Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernour or Deputy Governour, or any three or more of the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mittees of the ſaid Company for the time being, That the Moneys by him or her Subſcribed is his or her own proper Moneys, and that he or ſhe Subſcribes the ſame for his or her own Uſe, and not in Truſt, or for the uſe of any other Perſon or Perſons whatſoever;<note place="margin">The Governour, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> to Admi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſter the Oath.</note> To which ſaid Governour or Deputy Governour, or any three or more of the Committee of the ſaid Company for the time being, We do hereby
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:35892:3"/>for Us, Our Heirs and Succeſſors, give full Power and Authority; to give and Adminiſter the ſaid Oath, And do hereby Order and direct them, to adminiſter the ſame accordingly. <hi>Provided</hi> al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wayes, and our Will and Pleaſure is, And We do hereby for Us, Our Heirs and Succeſſors, ſtrictly require and command, and do order and direct, That all and every Perſon and Perſons, who ſhall make ſuch Subſcriptions as aforeſaid, ſhall at the time of ſuch Subſcription, actually and <hi>bona fide,</hi> pay down or cauſe to be paid down unto the Committee of the Treaſury of the ſaid Company for the time being, or their Caſhire,<note place="margin">A Third part of the Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcriptions to be paid down,</note> one full and entire Third part of the ſeveral Summes of Money, by each of them reſpectively Subſcribed to the ſaid preſent Joynt-Stock, and ſhall alſo pay the Remainder thereof on or at any time or times before the ſaid 10th. day of <hi>January</hi> now next coming. And further,<note place="margin">The reſt by the 10th. <hi>January.</hi>
               </note> Our Will and Pleaſure is, And We do by theſe preſents, for Us, our Heirs and Succeſſors, Grant unto the ſaid Governour and Company and their Succeſſors, and do hereby order and direct, That in all Gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral Courts of the Adventurers of the ſaid Company,<note place="margin">In all General Courts every Qualified Member having</note> Such Perſons (being Members of the ſaid Company, and qualified as is herein mentioned) ſhall have for and in reſpect of ſuch Summes, as they ſhall reſpectively have Subſcribed and paid in to the Joynt-Stock of the ſaid Company, ſuch number of Votes or Voices in a Ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neral Court of the ſaid Company, as are herein after limited and expreſs'd (That is to ſay) That each Perſon having One Thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſand pound or more in the Stock of the ſaid Company,<note place="margin">1000 <abbr>
                     <hi>l.</hi>
                  </abbr> Stock or more, ſhall have a Vote for every 1000 <abbr>
                     <hi>l.</hi>
                  </abbr> to 10000 <abbr>
                     <hi>l.</hi>
                  </abbr>
               </note> ſhall have one Vote for every Thouſand pounds, not exceeding Ten Thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſand pounds; and if Ten Thouſand pounds or more, yet that ſuch Perſon ſhall have but Ten Votes whatſoever his or her Stock be.<note place="margin">None to have more then Ten Votes,</note> And further, That no Perſon or Perſons who ſhall have in the Joynt-Stock of the ſaid Company, for his or her own uſe any Sum leſs than One Thouſand pounds,<note place="margin">And no Vote, if leſs than 1000 <abbr>
                     <hi>l.</hi>
                  </abbr>
               </note> ſhall have any Vote or Voice at a General Court of the ſaid Company for or in reſpect of ſuch Sum being leſs than One Thouſand pounds. And further, We will, and by theſe preſents for Us, Our Heirs and Succeſſors, do Grant unto the ſaid Governour and Company and their Succeſſors, And do alſo hereby Order and Appoint, That all and every Perſon and Perſons who were Members, or free of the ſaid Company by for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mer Charters or capable to be ſo,<note place="margin">All free of the Company by former Charters, or capable to be ſo:</note> And all other Perſons who ſhall Subſcribe and pay in any Sum of Money into the ſaid Joynt-Stock hereby appointed to be raiſed, in ſuch manner as is herein before directed, ſhall be admitted <hi>Gratis</hi> into the Freedom of the ſaid Company.<note place="margin">And all new Subſcribers to be free of the Company, <hi>gratis;</hi>
               </note> But that all and every Perſon and Perſons who ſhall not be ſo qualified as aforeſaid, but ſhall come in by purchaſe of any part of the ſaid General Joynt-Stock, ſhall take upon him or her the Freedom of the ſaid Company, and before his or her Admiſſion thereunto, ſhall pay or cauſe to be paid to the ſaid Governour and Company, and their Succeſſors, the Sum of Five pounds of Law<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful <hi>Engliſh</hi> Money,<note place="margin">Others to pay 5 <abbr>
                     <hi>l.</hi>
                  </abbr> for it;</note> by way of fine for his or her Admiſſion into the ſaid Freedom: And ſuch Perſon and Perſons, as alſo all Subſcribers to the ſaid Joynt-Stock,<note place="margin">who with the Subſcribers ſhall take the Oaths, <hi>Viz.</hi>
               </note> upon their Admiſſion ſhall take the Oaths appointed to be taken by a late Act of Parliament made in the Firſt Year of our Reign, Entituled, <hi>(An Act for the abrogating of the Oaths of Supremacy and Allegiance, and appointing other Oaths)</hi> and alſo the Oath uſually taken by all Perſons made Free of the ſaid Company, before the Governour or Deputy Governour of the
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:35892:4"/>ſaid Company for the time being, to whom We do hereby for Us, Our Heirs and Succeſſors, give Power and Authority to Adminiſter the ſaid Oaths accordingly. And further, We will, and by theſe Preſents for Us, Our Heirs and Succeſſors do grant unto the ſaid Governour and Company of Merchants of <hi>London</hi> Trading into the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> and their Succeſſors, That it ſhall and may be lawful to and for the Governour or Deputy Governour of the ſaid Company for the time being,<note place="margin">The Governour or Deputy Governour of the Company to call General Courts and Courts of Committees:</note> from time to time to call, and we do hereby order and direct, That they ſhall call a General Court, and Court of Committees, to be holden for the ſaid Company, which ſhall conſiſt only of ſuch Members of the ſaid Company, who ſhall at ſuch time have in the Joynt-Stock of the ſaid Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany,<note place="margin">To conſiſt of ſuch only as have a 1000 <abbr>
                     <hi>l.</hi>
                  </abbr> Stock each, in their own right, and have taken the ſaid Oaths.</note> the Sum of One Thouſand pounds at leaſt in his or her own Right, and ſhall have alſo taken the Oaths appointed to be by them taken as aforeſaid; (in which ſaid General Court or Court of Committees, the Governour or Deputy Governour of the ſaid Company for the time being ſhall be preſent,<note place="margin">The Governour or Deputy to have a Caſting Voice in ſuch Courts.</note> And in caſe of equality of Votes or Voices ſhall have a Caſting Voice). And further alſo, that all the Members of the ſaid Company ſo qualified as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, or the Major part of them, from time to time, and at all times hereafter, ſhall and may have power and Authority Yearly and every Year between the Tenth and laſt day of <hi>April,</hi> to aſſemble and meet together in ſome convenient Place to be appointed from time to time by the Governour,<note place="margin">Governour, Deputy, and 24 Committees, to be yearly choſen in <hi>April.</hi>
               </note> or in his abſence by the Deputy Governour of the ſaid Company for the time being: And that it ſhall and may be lawful to and for the ſaid Governour or Deputy of the ſaid Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernour, and other the Members of the ſaid Company, qualified as aforeſaid, for the time being, or the Major part of them, being ſo aſſembled in a General Court (whereof the Governour of the ſaid Company, or his Deputy for the time being to be one) to nominate and Elect out of the Members of the ſaid Company, a Governour, Deputy Governour, and Twenty Four Committees, each of them being reſpectively qualified to be choſen into the ſaid ſeveral Offices, in manner as herein after is expreſſed (That is to ſay) to nominate and Elect one of the Members of the ſaid Company, who ſhall then have in the Joynt-Stock of the ſaid Company,<note place="margin">The Governour to have 1000 <abbr>
                     <hi>l.</hi>
                  </abbr> Stock in his own right:</note> the Sum of Four Thouſand pounds at leaſt in his own Right, to be Governour of the ſaid Company for one whole Year from thence next following; and alſo one other of the Members of the ſaid Company, who ſhall then have in the Joynt-Stock of the ſaid Company, the Sum of Four Thouſand pounds at leaſt in his own Right,<note place="margin">The Deputy the ſame:</note> to be Deputy Governour of the ſaid Company for one whole year next enſuing; And alſo Twenty Four Members of the ſaid Company, who ſhall each of them then have in the Joynt-Stock of the ſaid Company,<note place="margin">The Committees each 1000 <abbr>
                     <hi>l.</hi>
                  </abbr>
               </note> the Sum of One Thouſand pounds at leaſt in his own Right, to be Commit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tees of the ſaid Company, for one whole Year from thence next en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſuing. And Moreover, Our Will and Pleaſure is, and by theſe Preſents for Us, Our Heirs and Succeſſors, We do grant unto the ſaid <hi>Governour and Company of Merchants of</hi> London <hi>Trading into the</hi> Eaſt-Indies, and their Succeſſors, and do hereby Order and Appoint, That when, and as often, as it ſhall happen, the Governour, De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>puty Governour, or any of the Committees of the ſaid Company for the time being, at any time within one Year after that they ſhall be Nominated, Elected and Sworn into their ſaid ſeveral Offices, to Die; that then, and ſo often it ſhall and may be lawful
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:35892:4"/>to and for the Reſidue of the Members of the ſaid Company,<note place="margin">If any die within the year, others (duly qualified) to be Elected in their ſtead.</note> quali<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fied as aforeſaid for the time being, or the major part of them, within convenient time after the Death of any ſuch Governour, Deputy Governour, or any of the Committees of the ſaid Company; to aſſemble themſelves in ſuch convenient place as they ſhall think fit, and in a General Court to Elect and Nominate ſome other Member or Members of the ſaid Company reſpectively qualified as aforeſaid, into the Office or Offices of Governour, Deputy Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernour, and Committees of the ſaid Company in the place and ſtead of him or them that ſo died; which Perſon and Perſons being ſo Elected and Nominated to the ſaid Office of Governour, Deputy Governour, or Committees of the ſaid Company, ſhall have and Execute the ſaid Office or Offices, for and during the reſidue of the ſaid Year. <hi>Provided alwayes,</hi> And our Will and Pleaſure is, And We do hereby for Us, our Heirs and Succeſſors, order, direct and appoint, that all and every Perſon and Perſons, who ſhall hereafter be Elected to the Office or Offices of Governour, Depu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty Governour or Committees of the ſaid Company, ſhall before they be admitted to the Execution of their ſeveral Offices,<note place="margin">The Governour, Depaty, and Committees before they Act to take the Oaths, <hi>Viz.</hi>
               </note> reſpective<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly take the Oaths before mentioned, and appointed to be taken by the ſaid late Act of Parliament, Intituled, <hi>An Act for the Abro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gating of the Oaths of Supremacy and Allegiance, and appointing other Oaths;</hi> and alſo the Oaths for the due and faithful Execution of their ſaid ſeveral Offices, before ſuch Perſons, and in ſuch manner as hath been heretofore uſed and accuſtomed, by vertue of any former Charters or Letters Patents, and this as often as the Caſe ſhall require. And further our Will and Pleaſure is, and by theſe Preſents for Us, our Heirs and Succeſſors, We do grant unto the ſaid <hi>Governour and Company of Merchants of</hi> London <hi>Trading into the</hi> Eaſt-Indies, and to their Succeſſors, That it ſhall and may be lawful to and for the ſaid Governour, and others the Members of the ſaid Company qualified as aforeſaid for the time being, from time to time to aſſemble themſelves for or about any the Matters, Cauſes, Affairs or Buſineſs of the ſaid Trade,<note place="margin">The Governour and other qualified Members of the Company may Aſſemble and hold General Courts where they pleaſe,</note> in any place or places for the ſame convenient, within our Dominions or elſewhere, and there to hold a General Court for the ſaid Company, and the Affairs thereof: And that alſo it ſhall and may be lawful to or for them, or the major part of them being ſo aſſembled, and that ſhall then and there be preſent in any ſuch place or places (whereof the Governour or his Deputy for the time being to be one) to make, ordain and conſtitute ſuch and ſo many reaſonable Laws,<note place="margin">and (the Governour or Depu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty being preſent) may make By-Laws for the Companies better Government,</note> Conſtitutions, Orders and Ordinances, as to them, or the greater part of them, being then and there preſent, ſhall ſeem neceſſary and convenient for the good Government of the ſame Company: And the ſame Laws, Conſtitutions, Orders and Ordinances ſo make, to put in uſe, and execute accordingly; and at their pleaſure to revoke or alter the ſame, or any of them, as Occaſion ſhall re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quire.<note place="margin">and revoke or alter them,</note> And that the ſaid Governour and Company ſo often as they ſhall make, ordain or eſtabliſh any ſuch Laws, Conſtitutions, Orders and Ordinances in form aforeſaid, ſhall and may impoſe, ordain, limit and provide ſuch lawful pains,<note place="margin">and may impoſe lawful Pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nalties, Fines, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </note> puniſhments and pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nalties, by Fines and Amerciaments, or by any other lawful ways and means, upon or againſt all Offenders contrary to ſuch Laws, Conſtitutions, Orders and Ordinances, or any of them, as to the ſaid Governour and Company for the time being, or the greater
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:35892:5"/>part of them, then and there being preſent (the ſaid Governour or his Deputy being alwayes One) ſhall ſeem neceſſary, requiſite and convenient for the obſervation of the ſame Laws, Conſtitutions, Orders and Ordinances; And the ſame Fines and Amerciaments, ſhall and may by their Officers and Servants, from time to time to be appointed for that purpoſe, levy, take and have to the uſe of the ſaid Governour and Company and their Succeſſors,<note place="margin">And levy the ſame to their own uſe.</note> without the impediment of Us, our Heirs or Succeſſors, or of any the Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cers or Miniſters of Us, our Heirs or Succeſſors, and without any account therefore to Us, our Heirs or Succeſſors to be rendered or made; All and ſingular which Laws, Conſtitutions, Orders and Ordinances ſo as aforeſaid to be made, We will to be duely ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerved and kept,<note place="margin">All which By-Laws ſhall be kept, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> if approved by a General Court, and not re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pugnant to the Laws of the Land.</note> under the pains and penalties therein to be con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tained, ſo alwayes as the ſaid Laws, Conſtitutions, Orders and Ordinances, Fines and Amerciaments, be firſt approved by a Ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neral Court of Adventurers, or the major part of them, for the time being, and ſo as the ſame be reaſonable, and not contrary or repugnant to the Laws, Statutes or Cuſtomes of this our Realm. <hi>Provided</hi> alwayes, and our further Will and Pleaſure is, and we do hereby for Us, our Heirs and Succeſſors, order and appoint, That the ſaid <hi>Governour and Company of Merchants of</hi> London <hi>Trading into the</hi> Eaſt Indies, or their Succeſſors, ſhall not at any time here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>after Licence or permit any Perſon or Perſons whatſoever, to Trade or Traffick,<note place="margin">No permiſſion to any Perſon to Trade, or Ships to paſs into, or from the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> on any private account,</note> or any Ship or Ships to Sail or paſs into, or from any part of the ſaid <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> on any Private Account whatſoever; and that if any ſuch Licenſe or Permiſſion ſhall be granted, contrary to our ſaid Order and appointment herein before declared, That then, and in each ſuch Caſe, as well theſe Preſents, as alſo the ſaid recited Letters Patents,<note place="margin">on Penalty of forfeiting this and the laſt Charter.</note> bearing date the Seventh day of <hi>October</hi> laſt paſt, and all and every the Powers, Grants, Matters and Things therein and herein contained, ſhall ceaſe, determine and be utterly void, to all Intents and Purpoſes, any thing to the contrary not<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>withſtanding. <hi>And We</hi> do further hereby for Us, our Heirs and Succeſſors, direct, order and appoint the ſaid Governour and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany, and their Succeſſors, That during the continuance of the ſaid Joynt-Stock of the ſaid Company,<note place="margin">No private Contract,</note> No private Contract for the Sale of any Goods or Merchandizes, ſhall be made by the ſaid Company, to any Member or Members of the ſaid Company, or any other Perſon or Perſons whatſoever (excepting only ſuch <hi>Salt-Petre</hi> as ſhall be ſold for the uſe of Us,<note place="margin">(excepting Salt-petre for the Crown)</note> our Heirs and Succeſſors): But that all Goods and Merchandizes belonging to the ſaid Company, ſhall be ſold openly and publickly by Inch of Candle,<note place="margin">but all Goods Sold at the Companies Candle, and for their account:</note> at their publick Sales upon the Companies Account; And that all Moneys ariſing by the Sale of any Goods or Merchandizes of the ſaid Company, ſhall be faithfully, and <hi>bona fide,</hi> accounted for, and applyed to the publick and common Benefit and Advantage of the General Joynt-Stock of the ſaid Company,<note place="margin">and the Money ariſing there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by applyed to the Companies uſe.</note> and of all and every the Perſons therein concerned, ratably and according to every perſons proportion and ſhare in the ſaid Joynt-Stock, and not to the private Advantage of any particular perſon or Perſons whatſoever. And that no Lot of any Goods or Merchandizes, ſhall be put up or Sold, which ſhall exceed the value of Five Hundred Pounds (Jewels excepted).<note place="margin">No Lot of Goods, except Jewels, to exceed 500 <abbr>
                     <hi>l.</hi>
                  </abbr>
               </note> And for the better In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>creaſe of Trade, and Encouraging the Exportation of Goods and Merchandizes, of the Growth, Product and Manufacture of this Kingdom, It is Our further Will and Pleaſure, and we do hereby
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:35892:5"/>for Us, our Heirs and Succeſſors, order and appoint, That the ſaid <hi>Governour and Company of Merchants of</hi> London <hi>Trading into the</hi> Eaſt-Indies, and their Succeſſors, ſhall Yearly and every Year, dur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the continuance of the ſaid Joynt-Stock, Export and carry to the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> Goods of the Growth, Product or Manufacture of this our Kingdom of <hi>England,</hi>
               <note place="margin">To Export yeatly to <hi>India</hi> 100000 <abbr>
                     <hi>l.</hi>
                  </abbr> worth of Goods of the Product, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> of <hi>England.</hi>
               </note> ſo many as ſhall amount to the Value of One Hundred Thouſand Pounds at the leaſt: <hi>Provided</hi> alwayes, and upon Condition, and the ſaid Governour and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany do hereby for themſelves, and their Succeſſors, Covenant, Grant and Agree to and with Us, our Heirs and Succeſſors, And we do hereby for Us, our Heirs and Succeſſors, order and appoint, that they the ſaid Governour and Company and their Succeſſors, ſhall Yearly and every Year, during the continuance of the ſaid Joynt-Stock, Furniſh,<note place="margin">To furniſn the Crown yearly with 500 Tons of Salt-petre at the Prices tollowing;</note> Sell and Deliver out of their Warehouſes in or near the City of <hi>London,</hi> unto the Officers of the Ordnance of Us, our Heirs and Succeſſors, or to ſuch other Perſon or Perſons as We, our Heirs or Succeſſors, ſhall in that behalf direct or appoint to Our and their Own Uſe, the Quantity of Five Hundred Tons of good, clean, and Mercantable <hi>Sal.-Petre,</hi> conſiſting of One Hundred and Twelve Pounds to the Hundred, when and as the ſame ſhall be required by the Maſter, Lieutenant, or other Chief Officer or Officers, of or belonging to the Ordnance of Us, our Heirs and Succeſſors, or by ſuch other Perſon or Perſons, as We, our Heirs and Succeſſors ſhall from time to time Appoint in that behalf, We, our Heirs and Succeſſors paying to the ſaid Governour and Company and their Succeſſors, for every Ton of ſuch <hi>Salt-Petre,</hi> the Summe of Thirty Eight pounds and Ten ſhillings of Lawful <hi>Engliſh</hi> Money in time of Peace, and in time of War, the Summe of Forty Five pounds of like Money for every Ton of ſuch <hi>Salt-Petre.</hi> And Our further Will and Pleaſure is, and We do hereby for Us, our Heirs and Succeſſors, Command, direct and appoint that all Dividends hereafter to be made of the Profits ari<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing by the Joynt-Stock of the ſaid Company,<note place="margin">All Dividends to be made in Money only.</note> ſhall from time to time be made in Money and not otherwiſe. <hi>And further,</hi> We do hereby for Us, our Heirs and Succeſſors, Order and Appoint the ſaid Governour and Company and their Succeſſors, that they,<note place="margin">The Companies Accomptant to Enter in a Book, or Books, from time to time, the Value of the Stock upon Oath;</note> and their Succeſſors ſhall Cauſe an Accomptant to keep a Book or Books in the Publick Office, or place of Meeting of the ſaid Company, to be provided for that purpoſe, and therein fairly enter or cauſe to be entered from time to time the true Value of the Joynt-Stock of the ſaid Company, the ſame to be by him atteſted upon Oath; which ſaid Book or Books, ſhall from time to time lie open to be Viewed, and peruſed by all Perſons concerned. And alſo that all Alienations, Mortgages,<note place="margin">And alſo all Alienations and Transfers of Stock</note> Transferrs and Aſſignments of any Part of the ſaid General Joynt-Stock, to any Perſon or Perſons whatſoever, ſhall be entered and Regiſtred by the ſaid Governour and Company and their Succeſſors, in the Publick, Ordinary and Common Book or Books to be provided by the ſaid Company for that purpoſe;<note place="margin">to lie open to the view of the Concerneds.</note> and that ſuch Common Book or Books ſhall lye open from time to time for the View of all Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons concerned. <hi>And</hi> our further Will and Pleaſure is,<note place="margin">The Joynt-Stock to continue 21 Years:</note> and We do hereby for Us, our Heirs and Succeſſors, Order, direct, limit and Appoint that the Joynt-Stock of the ſaid <hi>Governour and Company
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:35892:6"/>of Merchants of</hi> London <hi>Trading into the</hi> Eaſt-Indies, ſhall con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinue for Twenty One Years, to be computed from the date of theſe Preſents, and no longer, any thing herein, or in the ſaid recited Letters Patents, or any of them contained to the con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trary notwithſtanding.<note place="margin">A Year before which time Books for New Subſcriptions ſhall lie open for a New Joynt-Stock.</note> And alſo that during one whole Year next, before the Expiration of the ſaid Term of Twenty One Years, herein before mentioned for the continuance of the ſaid Joynt-Stock, the ſaid Governour and Company and their Succeſſors ſhall cauſe, and procure a Book or Books to be kept at their Publick Office or place of Meeting, to which ſaid Book or Books all Perſons being Natural Born Subjects, or Naturalized, or En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>denized, ſhall or may have free acceſs, and therein make new Subſcriptions, for the making a ſucceeding new General Joynt-Stock, as to Us, our Heirs or Succeſſors, ſhall ſeem meet and convenient.<note place="margin">Provided, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> as in the former Charter of the 7th. <hi>October.</hi>
               </note>
               <hi>Provided</hi> alwayes, and upon Condition nevertheleſs, and Our Expreſs Will and Meaning is, and We do hereby Order, Direct and Appoint, And the ſaid Governour and Company do hereby agree, That if the ſaid <hi>Governour and Company of Mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chants of</hi> London <hi>Trading into the</hi> Eaſt-Indies, and their Succeſſors, do not accept of, and from time to time, and at all times hereafter, Act according to, and put in due and effectual Execution, and ſubmit and conform in all things unto, as well all and every the Orders, Directions, Additions, Alterations, Reſtrictions, Qualifi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cations, Matters, and Things herein before expreſſed, as alſo all and every ſuch further and other Orders, Directions, Additions, Alterations, Reſtrictions and Qualifications, relating to the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtitution, Continuance, Determination, Rights, Powers or Privi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledges of the ſaid Company, or the Government thereof, or of the ſaid Governour and Company, or the Incouragement, Manage<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, Regulation or Advancement of Trade, or of the Preſent or future Joynt-Stock of the ſaid Company, or concerning any ſuture Subſcriptions, to be made by way of Increaſe, or Addition to the Joynt-Stock or for aſcertaining the true Values of the ſaid Joynt-Stock, at, and during the times of any ſuch future Subſcriptions, which, and as We, our Heirs or Succeſſors, by the Advice of Our or Their Privy Council, ſhall from time to time, at any time be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the 29th. day of <hi>September,</hi> which ſhall be in the Year 1694. think fit to make, inſert, limit, direct, appoint or Expreſs in, or by any further or other Charter, Letters Patents, or other Writing or Inſtrument, under our or their Great Seal of <hi>England;</hi> Then and in Each and every of the Caſes aforeſaid, It ſhall and may be lawful to and for Us, our Heirs, and Succeſſors by Letters Patents under our or their Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> to determine, revoke and make void, as well theſe Preſents, and the Grant hereby made, As alſo the ſaid Charter, or Letters Patents, bearing date the 7th. day of <hi>October</hi> laſt paſt herein before-mentioned, And all, and every, or any the Matters, and things therein, and herein contained, and from and immediately after the paſſing of ſuch Letters Patents of Revo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cation, or Determination under the Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> as well theſe Preſents, as alſo the ſaid Charter or Letters Patents bearing date the 7th. day of <hi>October</hi> laſt paſt, and all the Powers, Privi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledges, Grants, and other things therein, and herein contained, ſhall ceaſe, determine, and be abſolutely void, to all Intents and
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:35892:6"/>Purpoſes, Any thing to the Contrary notwithſtanding. <hi>In Witneſs</hi> whereof We have cauſed theſe our Letters to be made Patents, Witneſs Our Selves at <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> the 11th. day of <hi>November,</hi> in the Fifth Year of our Reign.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>
                  <hi>By Writ of Privy Seal,</hi> 
Pigott.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
